FERNANDO MARTURET

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT 786-859-5887 fernando.martu@gmail.com https://www.marturet.tech 668 Crystal Dr, Hendersonville, NC, 28791 SKILLS Technologies: HTML, CSS, TypeScript,

NodeJS, Bubble.io, Git, Python

Libraries: React, Express, MaterialUI, **TailwindCSS**

Databases: MongoDB, PostgresSQL, mySQL

Fluent in Spanish

EDUCATION

B.S in Psychology

Florida International University

2014-2018

PROFILE

Though I am not formally educated in Computer Science, I have had the pleasure of working alongside very talented software engineers for the last two years. I have worked on many personal projects as well as enterprise grade applications with a variety of front and backend technologies. I have worked with codeless tools like Bubble.io and can leverage the ability to build UIs quickly with such tools, while still knowing how to implement solutions with code. It turns out figuring out hacky solutions to circumvent the limitations of no code environments teaches you a lot about the browser and programming in general.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Lakeholdings (Fletcher, NC)

2022-present

- · Led the development and maintenance of diverse web applications, utilizing a technology stack encompassing HTML, CSS, TypeScript, NodeJS, Python and
- Contributed significantly to the growth of Canvasprints.com by actively participating in the development of the company's Management Information System (MIS) that tracks employee efficiency and monitors products/orders throughout the production process.
- Integrated with APIs and hardware to decrease manual labor in key steps of production and fulfillment.
- Developed Python scripts to automate key company processes and streamline operational workflows.
- Worked with databases such as MongoDB, PostgresSQL, and mySQL.
- Learned the importance of form validation in order to maintain clean and manageable databases long term
- · Adopted, improved and maintained legacy codebases
- · Cleaned and restructured existing databases using Python.
- Extended functionality of Bubble with NodeJS, Python and Vanilla Javascript to bypass data management and other limitations within the nocode platform.

Social Media/Sales Representative

OceanX (Arden, NC)

2018-2021

- · Actively engaged with customers through various social media platforms to enhance brand presence and build positive relationships.
- · Monitored and responded to customer inquiries, comments, and feedback on social media, contributing to a more dynamic and customer-centric online
- Demonstrated in-depth knowledge of multiple product lines, enabling the provision of accurate and detailed information to customers.
- Conducted product demonstrations and provided recommendations tailored to customer needs, contributing to increased customer satisfaction and loyalty.
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to streamline communication and ensure a seamless customer experience from sales inquiries to issue resolution.
- Worked closely with marketing teams to create and share engaging content on social media platforms, driving awareness and interest in the company's products.